Okay, so in this video,
let's discuss very high level,
very briefly we'll discuss the
ITTOs of scope management.
So ITTO's member are input tools and
techniques and outputs.
Now there are six processes then in scope
management and we're going to cover all
the important aspects of each of the
processes in subsequent videos.
But here are just some of the ITTOs.
Now also ITTOs, input tools and techniques
and outputs are not here.
huge major part of the exam anymore.
I mean, you need to understand them.
Don't get me wrong, you need to understand
them.
But you don't necessarily need to sit down
and memorize all of them.
As far as PIMBock is concerned,
there's 49 processes.
And each of those processes have many,
many ITTOs.
There's about 1,400 altogether.
So you just need to understand them.
You don't necessarily need to memorize all
of them.
Now, scope management then.
So remember, basically, what is,
what does they refer to?
An output is generally some form of
document, some form of artifact.
This is the artifact that we are going to
be creating in this process.
An input is usually also some form of
document, some form of artifact,
with exceptions, but these are what we
need to consider.
These are what we need
to review, what we need
to consider in order to create our output.
And then a tool and technique is,
this is what we need to do.
This is the action that we need to take,
right?
These are the tasks that we need to
perform, right?
Or these are the documents that we need to
utilize, right?
There's going to be some documents under
tools and techniques.
Those are documents that you need to
utilize in order to create our output,
right, in order to create our artifact.
So plan scope management then is
documenting how to develop the scope, right?
So any of these plan management processes,
for each of the knowledge areas from scope
management all the way down, right,
if you look at the process grid,
right, the process map, if you look at
scope management all the way down,
the very first process is always
plan something management,
and that's something
meaning that knowledge area.
So the first process in scope is planned
scope management, the first processing
schedule is planned
schedule management, first
processing cost is planned
cost management, etc.
Now, the output there, The
artifact that we're creating
is going to be the
appropriate management plan.
Remember, the management plan is
documenting how we're going to plan,
execute, monitoring, control, that
particular knowledge area.
So, and that's one of the components that
make up the project management plan.
So plan scope management
then is documenting how we're
going to develop the scope
and the requirements, right?
how they're going to be planned, executed,
monitored and
controlled, validated, right?
It doesn't actually contain the scope or
the requirements, it's documenting how.
So, since it's documenting how,
or this process is about how we're going
to develop the scope and the requirements,
and naturally, the artifact that we're
creating the output is
going to be the scope
management plan and the
requirements management plan.
Now, what's our starting point?
right?
What's our consideration to make?
Well, first starting point will be
reviewing the project charter.
The project charter may have some of those
procedures.
It may do, it may not do, but we would
refer to the project charter.
Also, components of the project management
plan.
So, quality management plan, the life
cycle approach, development approach.
So depending on whether it's a predictive
project or an agile project or an
iterative or an incremental, that can
determine how we're going to collect our
requirements, how we're going to develop
the scope of the project.
And then some external
factors, EF and OPA,
that can determine
procedures as well, right?
So enterprise environmental factor,
so internal procedures, that's going to
affect how we're going to develop the
scope, how we're going to develop the
requirements, plus maybe government
regulations, industry standards,
that can determine it as well.
Now, some of the tools and techniques,
well, first of all, expert judgment.
We see that in every process.
You're going to utilise their
own knowledge and experience
and the knowledge and
experience of others around you.
Also, alternatives.
What are the different ways of achieving
the same result?
I mean, alternative analysis is literally
as it sounds.
What are the different ways of meeting the
scope of the project and so and so forth?
Just like when, let's say, we're trying to
plan an event, right?
you know, like a product launch or
something.
I just kind of planning an event.
Well, there's different alternatives.
We can have different venues.
We'll still get the same result,
right?
But there's all these different venues
that we can choose from.
Alternatives.
I mean, alternatives analysis is literally
as it sounds.
And then, of course, we're going to be
having meetings over and over again.
So this was for planned scope management.
The other process then is
collect requirements, which
is what the customer wants,
what the customer needs.
You can see this is a very busy slide
here, right?
So again, you don't
need to learn all of these,
memorize all of them, just
have a decent understanding.
So collect requirements, where we are
rather in collect requirements,
we've got the requirements from the
customer, what we're documenting.
We are documenting the requirements,
where that documented, requirements
documentation, and the traceability
matrix.
Again, there's separate videos on each of
these.
What are some of the considerations to
make?
Well, some requirements
might be in the project charter,
so we might need to review
the project charter, right?
So we need to know how to collect
requirements, so that's going to be in the
management plans, right, scope and
requirements management plan.
We need to involve our stakeholders,
stakeholder engagement plan, right?
We might be looking at other project
documents as well, right?
Our agreements, right, our contracts,
that might have some requirements on them.
there, EF and OPA, right?
So that might determine our requirements.
So, for example, external
factors like regulations and
standards, that's going to
impact our requirements, right?
Or we might be reviewing historical
information, right?
Historical project files.
We've done a similar project before,
what were the requirements last time?
And then you can see that the whole bunch
of tools and techniques, I'm not going to
go through every one of these,
right?
Just have a quick review.
We have separate videos on each of these
tools and techniques.
all the important ones.
So again, you know, a tool and technique,
remember, is this is what we need to do.
This is the action that we need to take.
Or if there are any documents,
these are the documents that we need to
use in order to come up with the
requirements.
Then for defined scope, right, what
we're trying to create in defined scope.
The scope sets the boundaries of the
project.
What's included, what's not included,
right?
Where is that documented in the scope
statement, right?
So the output then is a scope statement.
That's what we're trying to create.
That's the artifact we're trying to
create.
What are some of the considerations?
Again, project charter may have high-level
scope, right?
So we might be reviewing the project
charter.
What else do we need?
We need some requirements.
That's why requirements documentation is
an input.
We need some requirements in order to be
able to scope out the project.
And then some of the tools and techniques,
again, we've got separate videos on these.
Again, we see alternatives analysis,
right?
What alternatives are there to meet the
same scope of the project?
So, the example I just
gave, we're doing an
event where we've got
all these different venues.
The end result might be
the same, but there's all
these different approaches
to get the end result.
Alternatives analysis is literally as it
sounds.
And then we've got a couple of these other
ones.
Again, we've got separate videos on those.
Now, some of the outputs
we're going to see is
this one here, project
document update, right?
In fact, most of the time we'll see those.
And those are just, you know, as a result
of, in this case, defining the scope,
there might be some
additional documents that we
need to update, and that's
what they're referred to.
Again, high level, work breakdown
structure.
We've got a whole separate
video on work breakdown structure,
which is a hierarchy of all
the work that needs to be done.
The output, what we're trying to create is
something called the scope baseline,
right?
And decomposition then, is the main
tooling technique.
What are there some of
the considerations then
for creating the work breakdown structure?
Well, we need to know
how, so scope management
plan is going to be documenting that.
And then plus, we need the scope,
we need the requirements, right?
And so that's why those are starting
points.
We need to review them, we need to
consider them.
Validate scope is a customer's acceptance,
again, a separate video on these.
It's a customer's acceptance of the
deliverable.
So if it's a customer's
acceptance of the deliverable, then
naturally the output is the
accepted deliverable, right?
Work performance information refers to the
interpretation, right?
What does it mean?
You're comparing the data with the plan.
Right.
So work performance information then
refers to things like are we head of
schedule, behind
schedule, over budget, under
budget, you know,
all of that kind of stuff.
What issues do we have?
Right.
So this will be part of validate scope as
well.
Has a customer
accepted it or have they got
an issue with the
product that we're doing?
Also then, one of the major tools and
techniques here, inspection.
Whenever you see the term inspection
anywhere, right, inspection means testing.
So in order for the customer to accept the
deliverable, they need to
test that deliverable, right?
They need to inspect it.
Right.
So similar to, again, when you're building
a house, right, when you're building a
house or you're doing some remodeling work
in your house, right you've hired
contractors to do the work you're the
customer right what are you doing as a
customer you're walking around seeing how
they're progressing right are they you
know building according to what you were
expecting right are the right colors on
the right walls and the right cabinets in
the right places and so and so forth right
what you are doing is inspecting right
you're basically you know observing
inspecting making sure that they're doing
what they're supposed to be doing and that
at the end right once they've delivered
that deliverable Once they've complete,
you're going to accept that deliverable.
Once you've accepted it, now we can go
into closing.
And one of the tools, one of the inputs,
if you like, for the closed project or
phase process was the accepted
deliverable.
And then ControlScope
is something that you, as a
project manager, is doing
throughout the project, right?
Properly controlling all changes to the
project.
And how do you control changes to the
project?
Right, well, you go through the change
control process.
which is covered in a, in a separate
video, right?
So, one of the key tools then,
again, work performance information,
because this is in monitoring controlling.
One of the key tools
of monitoring, one of the
key outputs is work
performance information.
One of the key outputs
of most of monitoring
controlling is work
performance information.
And then tools and techniques,
variance analysis.
Variance means, you know, a difference.
You're looking at your plan and your
actual results, right?
And that's a theme.
of monitoring controlling,
right, comparing
your plan with the actual results, right?
This is what we've done, this is what we
should have done.
Why is there a discrepancy?
That discrepancy is a variance.
And then the trend analysis is which way
we're trending, right?
Are we progressing?
I mean, how we're progressing over time?
Are we improving?
Are we decreasing our performance?
Some of the considerations
to make then, right, in
properly controlling the
scope of the project, right?
Well, again, components of the project
management plan what's our plan, right?
Actual results are other project documents
as well, right, requirements and
traceability matrix because
we're talking about the
scope here and then the
historical information as well.
That can help us.
Workformist data, right?
That's an important input for most of
monitoring controlling because what we're
doing is we're comparing actual results
with our plan.
Work performance data refers to actual
results and then we're comparing it with
our plan to get the interpretation,
which is the work performance information.
So these were then just some
of these were the ITTOs, the
input tools and techniques and
outputs of scope management.
Again, as with, you
know, all ITTOs, right,
you need to just have
a decent understanding.
Don't even try to memorize these as too
many.